## **BHAKTI PRAVIN PALKAR**

Jersey City, NJ 07306| bhaktipravin.palkar@pace.edu| (551)344-8186 | GitHub | Linkedin

### **PROFILE**

Software engineer with 2.8 years of experience building and testing applications in Oracle Utilities Application Framework; led improvement in performance of platform that serves 3.5 million customers, increasing speed by 30 percent; promoted once in first 16 months, six months ahead of schedule.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Pace University, Seidenberg School of Computer Science and Information Systems

New York, NY

Master of Science (MS) in Computer Science

September 2022 - May 2024

**University Of Mumbai** 

Mumbai, India

Bachelor of Engineering in Information Technology | **GPA:** 7.55/10

June 2015 - May 2019

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Accenture Solutions Pvt. Ltd.**

Mumbai, India

**Application Development Analyst** 

August 2019 – May 2022

- Analyzed, developed and tested 35+ release aligned problems, 100+ incidents reported by client using Oracle Utilities
  Application Framework Oracle MWM 2.3 and Oracle MDM 2.2 to meet client's requirements
- Executed production tasks like sanity checks, disaster recovery and patching support, query optimization and automation that helped increase the system performance by 70%
- Created "How To" (User Manual), Technical/Functional documents, FAQs and mentored new team members via knowledge transfer session that led to a 40% increase in productivity

M-Intellect Global Pvt. Ltd.

Mumbai, India

**Application Development Intern** 

June 2018 – July 2018

- Developed and tested modules of an On-Street Parking android application to help reduce time to find parking area and thereby reducing traffic issues by 40%
- Implemented using android studio which resulted in increase of revenue for government by 70%
- Collaborated with 4 product team members to implement new feature developments

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming/ Scripting Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, Python, R (Basic), C, XML, XPath, XQuery

Database and Database Management Languages: MySQL, Oracle, SQL, PL/SQL

Software Development: Git, CI/CD, Agile Development, Jenkins, GitHub

Software / Tools: Eclipse, NetBeans, Android Studio, Visual Studio, Junit Testing, Spring, JPA, Hibernate, Meter Data Management,

Mobile Workforce Management

Certifications: Oracle Certified Professional Java Programmer (OCPJP 6) | Certificate

#### **ACADEMIC PROJECTS / PERSONAL PROJECTS**

## Android Application for On-Street Parking using Android and Visual Studio

June 2018 - April 2019

- Enhanced internship project to develop end-to-end working application by using Asp.net, C#, Java, XML, SQL
- Prepared synopsis, power point presentation, black book and technical paper as part of the project

## Website – Recipe Keeper (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JSON, Ajax)

January 2017 - March 2017

- Designed front end of website to showcase recipes of traditional dishes of 9 Indian states
- Enhanced user experience by creating site structure, navigation, page optimization and graphics integration

#### Website of a resort (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js)

October 2016 - December 2016

- Built front end of website of a resort containing modules such as home, food & drinks, facilities, gallery and booking details
- Assessed UX and UI designs for technical feasibility using Adobe XD

# **ADDITIONAL TRAINING & CERTIFICATIONS**

**Technical Paper:** http://ijsart.com/Home/IssueDetail?id=29369 | ISSN NO.2395-1052

**Other Certifications:** Introduction to Python (Data Camp), Introduction to R (Data Camp), Introduction to scientific computing using Python - FOSSEE project IIT Bombay, Android Programming (KITE), Utilities Foundation Learning 2022 (Accenture) | Certificates **Awards:** Recognized as TechStar 2022 by Accenture Technology for outstanding contribution to client, people and Accenture